JISU RYOU

+821042422173 jisuryou7@gmail.com Portfolio Page I'm a junior UX engineer with a Master's degree in AI application services. I've primarily focused on conversational AI, having worked extensively with chatbots and voice agents. I'm also skilled in user experience research and can develop full-stack UX prototypes.

For more information about me, please check out my portfolio :)

Conversational AI Design

Full-stack Development

UX Research

Project Management

EDUCATION

Seoul National University, Korea - Sep 2021~Feb 2024

Master of Engineering

Dept. of Intelligence and Information, The Graduate School of Convergence Science and Technology (GSCST)

Advisor: Prof. Joongseek Lee

* (Best Paper) Study on a VA Journaling System: Focusing on Response Styles for Receiving Long Entries in VA Journaling

Sungkyunkwan University, Korea – Mar 2017~Aug 2021

Bachelor of Engineering and Bachelor of Science in Psychology (1st) Dept. of Software, College of Software Convergence (2nd) Dept. of Psychology, College of Social Sciences

The University of Texas at Dallas, United States – Jan 2019~May 2019 Exchange Student

EMPLOYMENT

SNU UXLab, Seoul, Korea – March 2024~Aug 2024 (6 months) Project Manager (Full-time)

- Led the project 'Financial Hyper-Personalization Using MyData'
 : Managed project, conducted desk research and user interviews,
 proposed strategic recommendations, performed data analysis, and designed service
- Led the project 'UX Evaluation of Text-Based Conversational Experiences'
 : Managed project, engineered LLM prompts and developed an evaluation system

SNU UXLab, Seoul, Korea – Sep 2021~Aug 2023 (2 years)

Student Researcher (Part-time)

- Participated in UX research for the project 'Advancing Financial Chatbots via Voice Banking'
 - : Conducted prototype testing and user interviews
- Led the project 'Dream Journal Voice Agent Development'
 - : Managed project, designed conversation flows, implemented technical solutions, conducted user interviews and analyzed data
- Participated in UX research for the project 'UX Improvement for Shopping Platforms'
 - : Analyzed shopping sequences and app UI layouts, and conducted user interviews
- Led the project 'Opportunity Discovery for Home Appliance Subscription Services'
 - : Managed project, conducted desk research and ideation, and proposed strategic recommendations
- Led the development phase of the project 'Exhibition Mind Robots Integrated with AI'
 - : Designed conversation flows and implemented technical solutions
- Led the development phase of the project 'Clothing Care Pilot for Shared Housing'
 - : Designed database and developed backend

Rihoz, Seoul, Korea – Sep 2020~Dec 2020 (4 months) Front-End Developer Intern (Full-time)

- Contributed to the project 'Dangjib (Your Smart Butler)', a big data driven smart life service platform
 - : Focused on front-end development of the admin web page and the production app

PUBLICATION

Ryou, J., Lee, K., & Lee, J. (2023, April). "You said da da...": A Short Echoing Tweak for Journaling with VA. In Extended Abstracts of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (pp. 1-6). [paper]

Lee, K., Ryou, J., & Lee, J. (2023). Study on the Mind-Upload of Construction-Building Method: A Case study on the Voice-based Conversation Robot Exhibition. In *Design Convergence Study*, 22(4), 59-73. [paper]

Kim, M., *Ryou, J., Lee, K., & Lee, J.* (2023). Actually, Clustering is Not Everything! How UXer analyzes behavior types with page log data. In *HCI KOREA*, 497-502. [paper]

Ryu, M., Park, S., <u>Ryou, J.</u>, & Lee, J. (2022). "Not a Replacement, But a New Form of Banking": Exploring VUI Use Cases for Banking via Human-Machine Communication. In *HCI KOREA*, 305-311. [paper]

Joongseek Lee, Minjoo Kim, <u>Jisu Ryou</u>, Kihun Lee (2023). 『1인가구와 기술: 혼삶의 시대, 기술이 만드는 이웃감』. threechairs. [book]

TALKS

Joongseek Lee, Sangah Park, <u>Jisu Ryou</u>, Sumin Kwon, Jiseon Yu (2022). "사용 할수록 지식베이스가 성장하는 대화형 서비스 만들기", *HCI KOREA 2022 Tutorial*.

SKILLS

Programming: Python(high), JavaScript(high), C(intermediate), C++ (intermediate), Java(intermediate), C#(low)

Technical: HTML/CSS(high), SQL(intermediate), R(intermediate), Dialog flow,

Google Cloud Platform

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, Figma

Language: Korean(native), English(fluent)